export const chapter = "Chapter - 4: The Delhi Sultanate ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who was the founder of the Slave Dynasty in Delhi?",
        optionA: "Prithviraj Chauhan",
        optionB: "Muhammad Ghori",
        optionC: "Qutb-ud-din Aibak",
        correctAnswer: "c) Qutb-ud-din Aibak",
      },
      {
        question: "Which dynasty ruled Delhi from 1206 to 1526 AD?",
        optionA: "Tomars",
        optionB: "Khalji Dynasty",
        optionC: "Lodi Dynasty",
        correctAnswer: "e) Slave Dynasty",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who is considered the real founder of the Sultanate period in Delhi?",
        optionA: "Prithviraj Chauhan",
        optionB: "Muhammad Ghori",
        optionC: "Shams-ud-din Iltutmish",
        correctAnswer: "c) Shams-ud-din Iltutmish",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who succeeded Qutb-ud-din Aibak as the ruler of Delhi in 1210?",
        optionA: "Prithviraj Chauhan",
        optionB: "Muhammad Ghori",
        optionC: "Shams-ud-din Iltutmish",
        correctAnswer: "c) Shams-ud-din Iltutmish",
      },
      {
        question: "Which dynasty ruled Delhi after the Khalji Dynasty?",
        optionA: "Slave Dynasty",
        optionB: "Tughluq Dynasty",
        optionC: "Lodi Dynasty",
        correctAnswer: "b) Tughluq Dynasty",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who is known as the most powerful ruler of the Khalji Dynasty?",
        optionA: "Shams-ud-din Iltutmish",
        optionB: "Jalal-ud-din Khalji",
        optionC: "Ala-ud-din Khalji",
        correctAnswer: "c) Ala-ud-din Khalji",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the primary source of revenue during Ala-ud-din Khalji's rule?",
        optionA: "Trade and commerce",
        optionB: "Agriculture",
        optionC: "Land revenue (kharaj)",
        correctAnswer: "c) Land revenue (kharaj)",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which ruler of the Tughluq Dynasty is known for facing numerous revolts and impractical new ideas?",
        optionA: "Shams-ud-din Iltutmish",
        optionB: "Muhammad-bin Tughluq",
        optionC: "Ghiyas-ud-din Tughluq",
        correctAnswer: "b) Muhammad-bin Tughluq",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What significant event marked the decline of the Tughluq Dynasty?",
        optionA: "Timur's invasion in 1398 AD",
        optionB: "Muhammad-bin Tughluq's death",
        optionC: "Firoz Shah Tughluq's ascension",
        correctAnswer: "a) Timur's invasion in 1398 AD",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who founded the Mughal dynasty in India after defeating Ibrahim Lodi in the first Battle of Panipat?",
        optionA: "Muhammad-bin Tughluq",
        optionB: "Firoz Shah Tughluq",
        optionC: "Babur",
        correctAnswer: "c) Babur",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The Tomars founded Dhillika or Delhi in the _______ century.",
        options: ["6th", "7th", "8th"],
        correctAnswer: "8th",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Prithviraj Chauhan was defeated by Mohammad Ghori in _______ AD.",
        options: ["1190", "1192", "1200"],
        correctAnswer: "1192",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Qutb-ud-din Aibak was declared the first Sultan of Delhi in _______.",
        options: ["1192", "1206"],
        correctAnswer: "1206",
      },
      {
        question: "The Sultanate period lasted from 1206 to _______ AD.",
        options: ["1451", "1526"],
        correctAnswer: "1526",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Shams-ud-din Iltutmish conquered many towns, including Bengal, Sindh, Ranthambor, Gwalior, Malwa, Ujjain, and _______.",
        options: ["Kashmir", "Bihar"],
        correctAnswer: "Bihar",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Ghiyas-ud-din Balban consolidated his territories and dealt with the nobles during his rule as the Sultan in _______.",
        options: ["1210", "1266"],
        correctAnswer: "1266",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Ala-ud-din Khalji expanded his sultanate and strengthened his army. He also regularized the administration and conquered Gujarat, Malwa, and _______.",
        options: ["Rajasthan", "South India"],
        correctAnswer: "Rajasthan",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Muhammad-bin Tughluq paid meager salary to his soldiers, but he fixed the prices of all essential commodities like grains, sugar, oils, and clothes. He appointed spies in different parts of his empire to keep him informed of the latest developments, including the soldiers' _______.",
        options: ["equipment", "faces"],
        correctAnswer: "faces",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Timur invaded India in _______ during the rule of the Tughluq dynasty.",
        options: ["1398", "1414"],
        correctAnswer: "1398",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who founded the Mughal dynasty in India after Babur's victory in the first Battle of Panipat in _______ AD.",
        options: ["1206", "1320", "1526"],
        correctAnswer: "1526",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "The Tomars founded Dhillika or Delhi in the 8th century.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Prithviraj Chauhan was defeated by Mohammad Ghori in 1192 AD.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Qutb-ud-din Aibak was declared the first Sultan of Delhi in 1206 AD.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "The Sultanate period lasted from 1206 to 1526 AD.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Shams-ud-din Iltutmish conquered many towns, including Bengal, Sindh, Ranthambor, Gwalior, Malwa, Ujjain, and Bihar.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Ghiyas-ud-din Balban consolidated his territories and dealt with the nobles during his rule as the Sultan in 1266 AD.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Ala-ud-din Khalji expanded his sultanate and strengthened his army. He also regularized the administration and conquered Gujarat, Malwa, and Rajasthan.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Muhammad-bin Tughluq paid meager salary to his soldiers, but he fixed the prices of all essential commodities like grains, sugar, oils, and clothes. He appointed spies in different parts of his empire to keep him informed of the latest developments, including the soldiers' faces.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Timur invaded India in 1398 AD during the rule of the Tughluq dynasty.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Mughal dynasty was founded in India after Babur's victory in the first Battle of Panipat in 1526 AD.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
